# 在家里边弄块面 几分钟就能吃上
Make a dough at home, it will be ready in a few minutes
# 现炖的牛肉 来一勺
Freshly stewed beef, have a spoonful
# 吃了一碗想两碗
Having the first bowl makes you think of the second
# 吃了两碗想三碗
Having the second bowl makes you think of the third
# 红烧牛肉饸饹面
Red braised beef with He Le noodles
# 这个肉 首选应该是选牛腱子
The meat. Beef shank should be the primary option
# 前腿的或者后腿的都行
Both foreshank and hindshank are good
# 但是今去市场去晚了 没买着
But I was too late when I went to the market, so I didn't get it
# 得 咱们就用肋条了
Alright. The rib it is
# 肋条的口感也特别好
The taste of ribs is also pretty good
# 跟牛腩差不多 肥瘦相间还带着筋
It's similar to beef brisket. Lean meat is interleaved with fat, with tendons attached
# 咱们给它一破二
Let's cut it in half
# 牛棒骨必须得有 我提前泡好水的
Shank bone is a must. I soaked it in water in advance
# 里边的骨髓满满
It's full of bone marrow inside
# 咱们这汤鲜还有香都靠它呢
The savory taste and aroma of our soup all count on it
# 咱给它凉水下到锅里来 冷水下锅
Let's put it in the wok with cold water
# 肉也是 这个肉都经过提前几个小时
The meat as well. The meat has been soaked in water for a couple of hours in advance
# 都浸泡的很干净了
so it's very clean
# 待会咱们把沫打一下
We'll remove the scum later
# 咱把这汤留下来
Let's keep the soup
# 大爷您20年前应该听说过一个
Da Ye, you should have heard it 20 years ago
# 咱北京特别有名
Very famous in Beijing
# 以前在东大桥那儿 有一饸饹面馆
In the past, near Dong Da Qiao, there was a He Le noodles restaurant
# 然后在北新桥这儿
And near Bei Xin Qiao
# 那时候我卖牛肉那几年
back in the few years when I sold beef
# 北新桥这儿也有一个
there was one near Bei Xin Qiao
# 红烧牛肉饸饹面
Red braised beef with He Le noodles
# 全是咱北京这块的老住户
Full of the old residents in Beijing
# 都特别爱吃这种面
Everyone loves this kind of noodles
# 饸饹床子在这儿呢 过去是木头的
The tool used for making He Le noodles was wooden in the past
# 木头底儿 这是自己做的
Wooden base. This is homemade
# 为什么饸饹床这么大
Why is the tool so big
# 因为它要架在灶台上
Because it will be set up above the cooktop
# 其实这饸饹面 过去真正在农村的时候
Actually the He Le noodles, back in time when we were in rural areas
# 他不是用的白面 都用的是棒子面
Wheat flour wasn't the one used for this, but cornflour
# 有的用莜面或者是荞麦面
Some people also used flour made from hulless oat or buckwheat,
# 加榆皮面 现在都改用白面了
together with elm bark. Now wheat flour is used for He Le everywhere
# 香料也很简单
Aromatics are also quite simple
# 我先把咱们烧肉的料先给它泡上
I'll first soak the aromatics used for meat stew in water
# 这个肉大概是二斤多肉
The meat is approximately a bit more than 2 jin (1 kg)
# 来几片香叶 大料来个四五瓣
Some bay leaves, and four or five star anise petals
# 小茴香来一点 都给了吧 别占着碗
Some fennel seeds. Just put in all of them. Don't take up the bowl
# 白蔻我得留两个
I am going to keep two pieces of white cardamom
# 因为待会儿咱们还得需要一点白蔻
Because we will have to use it shortly after
# 花椒得来点 都不要太多
Some Sichuan peppercorns. Everything is of a small amount
# 咱吃的是肉香
It is the aroma of meat that is to be tasted
# 桂皮来两小块
Two small pieces of cinnamon
# 白芷要少来 一小片就够了
Few baizhi. A small slice is enough
# 草果这个籽儿得要去掉
The seed of tsao-ko has to be removed
# 别弄太香了
Don't make the aroma too strong
# 我弄完了师父以后肯定
When I finish this, in the future, master will surely
# 一想这口就得找我
have to come to me when he wants to taste this
# 亮子 来一锅
Liangzi! Make me a wok!
# 一个是白芷 一个是小茴香 一个白蔻
Baizhi, fennel seed, white cardamom
# 这三个是最突出香味的东西
These three are the most useful for making the aroma stand out
# 他这料搭配的特别合理
His collocation of aromatics is quite wise
# 咱们还有一个肉蔻
We also have a nutmeg
# 这肉蔻一定要拿刀破开
The nutmeg have to be broken with a knife
# 不要多了 肉蔻要多了就夺味儿了
Don't put too much. Too much nutmeg will dominate the flavor
# 就一小块就行 三分之一
A small piece is enough. One third
# 用热水给它泡上
Soak them in hot water
# 在家里边想快一点 咱就给它煮一下
If you want to make it faster at home, we can boil it
# 熬一熬 搁里边泡上它
Decoct it for a while, and let it soak in it
# 泡完了这个料必须得炒出香味来
After soaking, the aromatics have to be cooked to bring out the aroma
# 让它激发出来 那太香了
Excite it and let it out. That would smell very nice
# 我们网友小饭骨
Our netizen Xiao Fan Gu
# 听到这些知识
After you've heard the knowledge
# 应该说一定要把它融进来
I should say, you surely gotta integrate it
# 才能达到这种好的效果
to reach such a good result
# 师父你看 剩下这点料
Look master, the rest of the aromatics
# 咱们干嘛 还有用呢
What to do with them? They are still useful
# 白蔻 再来一小块白芷
White cardamom, and a small piece of baizhi
# 这几片香叶都搁这里
Put these bay leaves here
# 大料瓣花椒也搁这里 全用完了
Also put star anise petals and Sichuan peppercorns. We used them up
# 肉蔻也是搁一小块 越少越好
nutmeg shall also be a small piece. The less the better
# 这个料是干嘛 待会咱们给它熬酱油汁
What are these aromatics for? We will use it to decoct soy sauce later
# 因为红烧牛肉面 离不开这酱油的
Because you can't have red braised beef noodles without the soy sauce
# 你看这酱油不是说
See, the soy sauce isn't like
# 拿起一个酱油就能做的
it can be made just with any soy sauce
# 这是熬制酱油 就是要它一个复合味
This is decocted soy sauce. It's aimed at a composite flavor
# 咱们这里边
In this
# 就是刚才咱们留下来这点香料
In the aromatics left just now
# 配一点洋葱 胡萝卜
add some onions and carrots
# 葱 姜 香菜（和尖椒）
spring onion, ginger, cilantro (and chili pepper)
# 待会咱们熬一个酱油汁
We will use them to made decocted soy sauce later
# 得 这个料开了
Ok. The aromatics are boiled
# 咱给它倒在这盆里头 给它泡上
Let's put them in the bowl and let them soaked there
# 越泡味越重
The longer the soak is, the stronger the flavor is
# 现在这个料煮完了给它泡一会儿
Now that the aromatics are boiled, soak them for a while
# 料渣篦出来 这水不要了
Filter out the dregs of aromatics. We can pour the water away
# 香料水就不用了 用不着了
We won't use water used for aromatics
# 这个香料待会咱们拿它来烧牛肉
Later on, we will use the aromatics to cook beef
# 然后这个酱油汁它是有比例的
And there is proportion in the decocted soy sauce
# 这水是七两的水  三两半的酱油
7 liang (350 g) water. 3 and a half liang (175 g) soy sauce
# 水是酱油的一倍
Water is twice the soy sauce
# 然后这个放进去之后
And after we put this in
# 蔬菜咱就搁进去就行了
we can just put in the vegetables
# 然后我先调一个味儿
And I'll season it first
# 白胡椒粉 你要喜欢就多放
White pepper. You can put more if you like
# 盐 来两大勺
Salt. Two tablespoons
# 鱼露 鱼露是增鲜的
Fish sauce. Fish sauce is used to enhance the umami taste
# 鲜味汁 就跟鱼露一样多就行了
savory sauce. Just as much as the fish sauce is okay
# 增加香气 是增香的 错不了
Enhance the aroma. It enhances the aroma. Definitely
# 还得跟点糖
Also followed by some sugar
# 让它有一点微微的回甘就行
A mild sweet taste in a deeper layer of flavor is sufficient
# 这样煮个三五分钟就行了
Keep boiling for 3 to 5 minutes, and it'll be ready
# 泡着 待会咱们还得拿它调汤呢
Let it soaked here. We will need it to season the soup later
# 就这骨髓 师父您看这骨髓 太棒了
The marrow. Look at the marrow, master. Really nice
# 红烧牛肉面主要就在吊这汤上
The core of making red braised beef noodles is to make the soup
# 尤其现炖的牛肉
Especially freshly stewed beef
# 不用加味精就鲜 真香啊
It can be savory without MSG. Smells really good
# 咱这棒骨出来这些沫 咱给它打掉
Let's remove the the scum from the bone
# 有油也给它打掉
Remove the oil as well if there's any
# 咱们吊汤的时候
When we make the soup
# 葱姜是为了去它的腥膻味
Spring onion and ginger are used to remove its taint and gamey taste
# 咱为了快速
To be fast
# 把牛肉和棒骨搁在高压锅里边
we'll put the beef and the bone in the pressure cooker
# 二十五分钟
25 minutes
# 肉压的到时候了 看看
It's time! Take a look
# 实际上最主要是要这汤
Actually we're mainly aiming at the soup
# 这牛肉正合适
The beef is just well cooked
# 咱们先把肉给它炖上
Let's first stew the meat
# 肉的块一定要得够个儿
The size of beef blocks gotta be large enough
# 切的非常整齐
It's neatly cut
# 它趁着热做和凉着做不一样 绝了
It's different if you cook it while it's hot or cold. Fantastic
# 这个底油加上之后
After we add the base oil
# 直接就放进去了 料油
we can put it in right away. Aromatics oil
# 小火慢慢炸 炸香
Slowly fry it with mild heat. Bring out the aroma
# 直接倒里了 这一出香味就行
Just pour it in. Once the aroma is out, it's okay
# 不要炸的特别金黄色 这不用
Don't fry it until it's golden yellow. It's not necessary for this
# 这料油啊 葱姜 下料狠
This is aromatics oil. Spring onion, ginger. You used a lot of aromatics
# 这还要么 这得留着
Do we keep this? We have to keep this
# 待会咱们调好汤 得煮它一下
After the soup is done, we gotta boil it
# 葱姜一炸到金黄色 出香了
Once the spring onion and ginger is fried to golden yellow and aroma is brought out
# 这肉就可以搁进去了
we can put the meat in the wok
# 煸炒这步很重要 一定要大火煸炒
The stir frying step is really important. It has to be cooked with strong heat
# 白酒 这个白酒是清香
Baijiu. This baijiu is of Fen-flavor
# 能把牛肉的清香带出来
It can bring out the natural aroma of beef
# 烹完酒之后烹酱酒
Baijiu is followed by soy sauce
# 这是酱油 要黄豆酱油
This is soy sauce. We need soy sauce made from soybean
# 这酒香味儿真足
The aroma of the liquor is strong
# 吃牛肉面 咱们最好是用白酒
It's better to use baijiu for beef noodles
# 因为白酒它度数高 挥发的快
Because the alcohol content is high in baijiu, it volatilizes fast
# 然后咱们给它煸炒一会儿 香味出来了
And we stir fry it for a while. The aroma has been brought out
# 要加什么 就咱们这个棒骨汤
What to add? The shank bone soup
# 这个牛肉一定要烧到让它特别烂乎
The beef has to be stewed until it's soft and tender
# 咱们先调味
Let's season it first
# 这个口一定要到位  三大勺盐
It has to be savory enough. Three tablespoons salt
# 少来一点白胡椒粉
A little bit white pepper powder
# 这个是调味的
These are for the seasoning
# 待会咱们调汤的时候还要搁
We will still add some when we season the soup
# 开锅之后 咱们先把料包给它包上
After it's boiling, let's first wrap up the aromatics bag
# 煮个10分钟以后
After 10 minutes boiling
# 咱们把肉给它直接捞出来
let's just take out the meat
# 要去掉葱姜
We need to throw away the spring onion and ginger
# 这肉炖出来利索
The stewed meat will be immaculate
# 拣料这个过程
The process of picking out the aromatics
# 您不论烧什么肉都得有 菜是做的干净
is inevitable for all kinds of meat stew. Cuisines are to be tidy
# 咱们得调一下颜色
We gotta adjust the color
# 红烧牛肉颜色也是很重要的
Color is also important for red braised beef
# 这颜色可以使什么调
What can be used to adjust the color?
# 您可以使糖色调
You can use caramelized sugar
# 也可以使冰糖老抽调
You can also use white rock sugar dark soy sauce
# 咱家里边就老抽就行
Dark soy sauce would be fine when cooking at home
# 这个料包搁进去煮着去吧
Put in the aromatics bag and let it be boiled there
# 牛棒骨咱们调汤 一会就能吃了
Let's season the soup. It will be ready to eat soon
# 大家看这汤了么
You see the soup?
# 牛肉面一定要有这种好汤
The soup of this good quality is necessary for beef noodles
# 两勺 两勺酱油汁
Two spoons. Two spoons decocted soy sauce
# 少跟一点糖
followed by a little sugar
# 盐
Salt
# 白胡椒粉 这个量得大一点
White pepper powder. This should be of a large amount
# 因为汤底 胡椒的味道
Because it's in the base soup, the flavor of pepper
# 让它冲一点没事 要充分
could be a bit strong. Gotta be ample
# 齐了 这汤就好了
All checked. The soup is ready
# 好 下面
Good. Cook the noodles
# 咱们平常在家里边
Normally when we make this at home
# 这个面也别太硬
the dough shouldn't be too hard
# 一斤面六两水
1 jin (500 g) flour with 6 liang (300 g) water
# 然后来上一小勺盐就够了
And then a teaspoon salt should be enough
# 锅一开了 您就可以把面搁进去
Once it's boiling, you can put in the noodles
# 你这劲儿还不小
You have a strong hand
# 因为这个 汤调好了肉炖好了 特别快
Because this, once soup and meat are well prepared and stewed, is quite fast
# 在家里边弄块面 几分钟就能吃上
Make a dough at home, you can have it within a few minutes
# 那咱就浇汤了
We'll add the soup then
# 现炖的牛肉 来一勺 四块到六块
Have a spoonful of freshly stewed beef. 4 to 6 blocks
# 红烧牛肉压饸饹
Red braised beef with pressed He Le noodles
# 可以说这是我吃饸饹面
I could say that this is the best He Le noodles
# 有生以来 最好的最香的一次
with the richest aroma I've ever had in my life
# 一个是面滑 面软 筋道
On the one hand, the noodles are silky, soft and chewy
# 汤鲜肉烂
Savory soup. Tender and soft meat
# 牛肉就得大块
Beef has to be in large blocks
# 然后让它炖的烂乎
and stewed until it's tender and soft
# 他这料加的好 又不夺肉的香味
His aromatics are well chosen, without suppressing the aroma from beef
# 这个料要是把肉味压没了
If the flavor of aromatics dominates over the flavor of meat
# 红烧牛肉这味就吃不出来了
you can't really taste red braised beef then
# 完全是肉的香味
This is completely aroma of the meat
# 而且这大棒骨配得好
Also, the big shank bone is a perfect match
# 要不然光牛肉这点油 脂肪达不到
Otherwise, the fat wouldn't be enough merely with the little fat from the beef
# 没吃够啊 再来点汤
I'm not having enough. More soup
# 再来一碗没事
Come on have a second bowl of it
# 小亮这个调料用活了
Liang used the aromatics vividly
# 料香肉香 各种香气融合一体
Aroma from aromatics and meat. All kinds of aroma are mixed
# 吃了一碗想两碗
Having the first bowl makes you think of the second
# 吃了两碗想三碗
Having the second bowl makes you think of the third